### Contact

5656 Kelley St Houston TX 77026 7135664228 (Work) louly.contreras@harrishealt h.org

www.linkedin.com/in/louly-contreras-221b9314a (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

Management
Presentation Skills
Leadership Development

### Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)
Spanish (Professional Working)

### Honors-Awards

Good Sameritan Foundation Bronze Medalist

# **Louly Contreras**

Clinical Resource Nurse II at Harris Health System Houston, Texas Area

## Summary

Experienced Nurse Leader and educator with a demonstrated history of working in the hospital & health care industry. Skilled in Multiple Project Coordination, Presentation Skills, Team Building, Spanish, and Management. Strong healthcare services professional with a Master's degree in Nursing from The University of Texas Medical Branch at Galveston.

# Experience

Harris Health System 8 years 11 months

Clinical Resource Nurse II May 2019 - Present (1 year 1 month) Houston, Texas Area

Nursing Professional Development Specialist March 2017 - Present (3 years 3 months) Houston, Texas Area

- Nursing Residency Program Coordinator
- Coordinate Schools of Nursing Clinical Placements for Harris Health System
- Nursing Education Website Developer

Nursing Clinical Manager October 2014 - March 2017 (2 years 6 months)

Houston, Texas Area

- -Coaches nursing staff and ancillary services in implementing nursing professional practice model (i.e evidence based practice/care plans, fostering shared governance, evaluating compliance and correcting practice variances)
- -Demonstrates advanced knowledge in all services provided with specialty in trauma
- -Addresses problem resolution using collaborative approach
- -Assists in recruitment; developed a nursing internship relationship with UTMB to recruit nursing staff

-Maintains positive work environment with staff, physicians, and patients by maintaining open communication and team work approach to nursing leadership

#### Nurse Clinician

July 2011 - October 2014 (3 years 4 months)

Houston, Texas Area

- -Functions as charge nurse on all shifts.
- -EPIC OPTIME preference card creator (Nursing Informatics Lead)
- -Developed multiple PowerPoint Presentations and creation of Post-Mortem Checklist to aide all nurses in their clinical practice.
- -Successful completion of multiple classes in improving leadership skills such as: Conflict Management, Unlocking Staff Potential, Introduction to Nursing Leadership, and Developing Charge Nurse Excellence

## Education

The University of Texas Medical Branch
Master's degree, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (2017 - 2019)

San Jacinto College

Associate of Arts - AA, Biology, General · (2007 - 2009)